Filipe Costa da Silva Rocha

7th January 1980

Creating architectural 3d renderings since 2004. I have experience working in large and fast paced environments with tight deadlines like *Euro RSCG* – Design & Architecture, where I was responsible for delivering 2D/3D images and animations for "Sonae", "BES", "Vichy", "Peugeot". In 2008 I worked on the "Optimus" rebranding, the biggest investment in rebranding ever made at the time in Portugal. I also worked in a small architecture office and did freelancing.

In 2007 and 2008 I was invited to teach 3D Animation workshops in the Portuguese movie festival "Caminhos do cinema Português" and in late 2008 I became an ATC 3ds Max Instructor at "The edge – Digital Visual Effects Training".

I am passionate about CGI and teaching, I like keeping up to date about CG software and workflows and to be part of visual projects, from concept to end result.

Key Skills:

ney Skills:	
2D	 Photoshop Camera Raw; Photo Manipulation; Concept Painting. Illustrator Vector drawing and illustration; concept design; Photography
3D	 3Ds Max Modeling; Lighting; Rigging; Animation; Render. V-Ray; Mental Ray; FumeFX; Particles; MaxScript; Backburner. Mudbox Digital sculpting and normal map creation. Real Flow Fluids simulation.
Video	 After effects \ Nuke Motion Graphics, 2D animation, Digital video effects and colour grading; video post production. Premiere Video editing. Encore DVD\Blu-ray interactive menus.
Web	 Dreamweaver Html; CSS; Javascript. Flash Animation
Other	 Cubase – Audio production MS Office.

Education and Training:

Laucation and maining.	
I.E.F.P - Oct 2014 \ Mar 2016:Certificate of higher education (NVQ 4)	INSTITUTO DO EMPREGO E FORMAÇÃO PROFISSIONAL
	Multimedia technician
I-zone – Sep 2011 \ Nov 2011Certified trainer	k n o w l e d g e • s y s t e m s people processes technology
	Pedagogical Aptitude training course

Relevant experience:

itelevant expendice.		
December 2013 – march 2014:	Project: O voo da águia ("the flight of the eagle").	
Iniziomedia Produções & LX3D Atitude Virtual	 responsibilities: Build and prepare the computers used by the vfx team. Coordinate and supervise the 3ds Max team. 3D environment modelling, animation and rendering. 	
October 2008 – September 2011:	Role: 3ds Max instructor.	
The Edge, Digital visual effects training.	 Responsibilities: Prepare and structure 3ds Max courses for Autodesk certification. Lecture 3ds Max for beginners and advanced users. Made software presentations in job fairs and schools. 	
June 2007 – January 2008 and April 2012 – September 2012:	Role: 2D and 3D artist. Projects: Optimus rebranding, Vichy package	
Euro RSCG worldwide Design & Architecture.	and stand design, Bes, peugot, continente, TMN.	
	 Created 2D and 3D imagery to show rebranding ideas to the client. Created 3D imagery for a variety of purposes and projects. 	

August 2009	Role:
Fotosport	Event photographer (freelance)
September 2008 – April 2009	Role:
	3d architectural visualizer \ artist
	Project: City of Lisbon in 3D
LX3D – Atitude Virtual	Responsibilities:
	 3D modeling; texturing; lighting and rendering from architecture technical drawings, concept drawings and photographs
2007 & 2008:	Role:
"Caminhos do cinema Português" film festival.	3d animation workshop instructor.
November 2004- January 2006:	Role:
	3d architectural visualizer
Arquitecto Luis Neto & Associados.	Responsibilities:
	 3D modeling; texturing; lighting and rendering from architecture technical drawings. Photography. Create 2D Images.

Freelance collaborations:

Company	Project type
LX3D Atitude Virtual	Dedicated 3D Visualization Office
Ligne Roset	Interior Design
Almendra Maria Architects	Architecture Office
SIC	Golden globes stage design pre- visualization
Stamina Productions	3D and fluids animations

Interests:

I enjoy playing with peoples emotions through storytelling, images and sound. I am passionate about Cinema, Music and photography, studied violin as a child and now I play guitar and piano. I also enjoy reading, specially if it's science fiction or physics related. I always self improve my skills and knowledge by following online tutorials and taking courses on several subjects of interest.

Driver's licence A+B

Email:Website:Mobile:FilipeCSRocha@gmail.comfilipecsrocha.github.io/07709075465